

# **Setsoto Hlohlomi**

ADDRESS 1 : Ha Matala, Maseru Lesotho
ADDRESS 2 : Can relocate to Gauteng, South

Africa

**VISA NUM**: JNGSFCQ (Critical Skills Visa in IT)

PHONES: (+266)58565709
EMAIL: shlohlomi@gmail.com

CITIZENSHIP: MOSOTHO
GENDER: FEMALE

LANGUAGES: ENGLISH, SESOTHO

# **Objectives**

To pursue a challenging career and professional environment which encourages learning, where my knowledge can be shared and enriched for the growth of the organization and self and needing to relocate to South Africa due to family reasons

#### **Profile**

System Administrator possessing MCSA Server 2012 with skills in Windows Server and Client Operating systems, Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, VMWare, SCCM, SQL, Software and Hardware support and some experience with Java, HTML, CSS. Resourceful with troubleshooting and problem solving skills obtained in the IT department with a BEng Degree in Computer Systems and Networks (NQF 8 by SAQA Evaluation)

LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/setsoto-hlohlomi-450a7a75

Github : <a href="https://github.com/setsotohlohlomi">https://github.com/setsotohlohlomi</a>
Website : <a href="https://setsotohlohlomi.github.io/">https://setsotohlohlomi.github.io/</a>

## **Skills Matrix**

Had appropriate training only

2. Limited working experience

3. Solid practical experience

4. Well versed, extensive experience

5. Expert, extensive work experience

Skill Type/Technology	Skill Level	Years of Experience	Last Used
Java core, android	2	1.0	2015
Java FX	2	0.5	2015
OOP	2	1.0	2015
HTML,Bootstrap,CSS	2	1.0	Current
Github	2	0.5	Current
Windows server (2003,2008,2012)	4	2.5	Current
Active Directory, Group Policy	4	2.0	Current
DNS, DHCP	4	2.0	Current
File and Print services, DFS Replication	4	2.0	Current
MS Lync Client 2010,2013	3	2.0	Current
Windows Client(7,8.1,10)	4	2.5	Current
Skype for business client 2015	3	1.0	Current
MS Office(2010, 2013)	4	3.0	Current

Skill Type/Technology	Skill Level	Years of Experience	Last Used
MS SQL Server 2012	2	1.0	Current
BMC Remedy Incident Management	3	2.5	Current
Remote Desktop Services	3	1.0	Current
VMWare(Host &VM Management)	3	1.5	Current
SCCM	3	1.0	Current
Unix Administration	1		
Microsoft Exchange Server	2	0.5	Current
Skype for Business Server	2	0.5	Current
Xerox and Konika Minolta Printer Support(Basic troubleshooting, toner replacement, paper jam removal)	3	2.0	Current
P C Hardware support(Removal, or RAM, HD, Monitors)	3	3.0	Current
HP IRS server Hardware monitoring	3	1.5	Current

### **Employment History**

Company: Vodacom Lesotho

Position : Specialist IT Operations (June 2015 – Present)

Duties :

- Installation and configuration of windows servers and client PCs
- Setting up SCCM architecture and administration of windows devices using SCCM
- Administration of active directory roles in the organization, Creation and modification of advanced group policy objects application compatibility, account security and organization standardization
- Configuration and management of DHCP servers and the corporate DNS Servers
- Supporting Exchange Clients, Webmail and Skype for Business rights allocation
- Management of the Virtual platform for both production and disaster recovery ESXi 5.5 Hosts
  with Training in v6, Creation, Configuration, Cloning, Deletion (clean-up) of VMs and
  reconfiguration of ESXi hosts as required using VSphere, Liaise with Suppliers and Support for
  upgrades of ESXi Hosts when host resources have been depleted
- Setting up a geographically redundant architecture for Active directory, SMTP, File server,
   Print Server and System performance reporting
- Creation of a central storage for the organizations documents and configuring active directory authentication for secure access to folders on the file server, configuring DFS replication to synchronize changes to a backup server for redundancy, file screening and quota management
- Administering print servers which enable centralized printing, troubleshooting of printer models like Konica Minolta, HP and Xerox devices for basic error resolution and escalation to suppliers when necessary
- Support of software and hardware issues pertaining to client PCs. Basic part replacement, Hard drives and RAM, monitoring of Server Hardware using HP IRS for proactive notification of hardware failures to the Department and to HP

Company: Vodacom Lesotho

Position : Intern: Service desk (Feb 2015 – May 2015)

Duties :

- Technical support of windows client operating systems and basic hardware parts replacement
- Logging and tracking of incidents for clients

- Service desk reporting and analysis of improvement or discrepancy in resolution of incidents
- Follow up on client incidents to ensure satisfactory resolution of incidents

Company : National University of Lesotho

Position : Java Demonstrator Date : 2013(Sept - Nov)

Duties :

 Assisting students during labs during the course of the Java programming Language with exercises

 Clarification and tutoring for Java core concepts such as OOP, Classes, Functions and assisting with Database connections from Java – MySQL

#### **Corporate Achievements**

- ✓ Successfully deployed a single site System Centre Configuration Manager which I am currently using to upgrade client PCs to Windows 10, reporting and pushing of software's
- ✓ Successfully created a custom Windows 10 image with all the necessary software's in order to make deployment and configuration of windows clients easier
- ✓ Successful completion of user and mailbox migration from the local Vodacom active Directory domain to a global Vodafone domain for standardization
- ✓ Liaised with support for implementation of a new VMWare ESXi Host and migration VMs to the new Host
- ✓ Group policy remodelling to reinforce user accounts security using group policy objects and passwords conforming to minimum requirements
- ✓ Cost cutting on server hardware contracts by compiling an up to date corporate server inventory of existing commissioned servers
- ✓ Obtained best team award for organizing training and empowering first line technical support at retail stores which enabled faster resolution times for IT related incidents at Vodacom Lesotho
- ✓ Successful deployment of an Active Directory, File server and print server Disaster recovery server for geographical redundancy

#### **Personal Achievements**

- ✓ Most inspiring woman award at African Women's Month Awards
- √ 4<sup>th</sup> and 1<sup>st</sup> Prize winner at the NUL HACKATHON 2013/2014 and 2014/2015(respectively) all night programming competition sponsored by Vodacom
- ✓ Best student in computer systems and networks 2015 awarded by Econet Telecom Lesotho for being the best graduate in the course
- ✓ Best student in Cisco networking 2015 for being the best performing graduate in the Cisco Curriculum
- ✓ Best student in ICT 2015 for being the best ICT student
- ✓ Best female student in Cisco networking 2014 for being the best performing student in the Cisco Curriculum

Education			
Qualification	Institution	Duration	
Microsoft Certified Solutions	Microsoft	Nov 2017	
Associate: Windows Server 2012			

Administering Windows Server	Microsoft	April 2017
2012 (Exam 70411)		
Training for Configuring	Torque IT	Feb 2017
Advanced Windows Server 2012		
Microsoft Certified Professional	Microsoft	July 2016
(Exam 70410)		
Training for VMWare v6, Install,	HP Rovinia	June 2016
Configure and Manage		
Unix System Administration	Internet Society	Nov 2015
Bachelor of Engineering in	The National University of	2010 - 2015
Computer Systems and Networks	Lesotho	
(SAQA NQF 8)		
C.O.S.C (First Class, Top 4)	Ts'akholo High School	2008 - 2009

### Other projects

- Java Desktop Maze game a simple windows application with several levels
- Java Desktop MAC address finder over Wi-Fi connection which tracks PC's with a mac addresses when connected to a Wi-Fi hotspot and won me 4<sup>th</sup> Place at the first NUL Hackathon
- Track My Droid(Java-Android) detects SIM change in a stolen phone and sends the new number to contacts specified before the theft, aiding in tracking by the authorities and won me first place in the second NUL hackathon
- Face Recognition and RFID Security System(final year project)

#### **Personal Qualities and Interests**

- Hard working and dedicated with good interpersonal and relational skills
- Quick and constant learning, resourceful and no supervision required due to passion
- Analytical and Social with good verbal and communication skills
- Reading, Swimming, Playing the piano, travelling and learning new places

#### References

1. LEBAMANG MOHAI

Senior Manager: Core Networks, Vodacom Lesotho

Email: Lebamang.Mohai@vodacom.co.ls

Phone: +266 5221 2298

2. KOPANO MOEKETSI

Lecturer: National university of Lesotho

Email : <a href="mailto:fk.moeketsi@nul.ls">fk.moeketsi@nul.ls</a>
Phone : +266 5221 3514

3. MAMOTHOKOANE TLALI

Manager: LsNIC, Lesotho Communications Authority

Email: Mtlali@lca.org.ls Phone: +2665 222 1300